okay let's start now first everybody I
want you to open the open the canvas and
go to the home page
make sure you read the syllabus so the
requirement is on the syllabus this
particular course for
for the computational foundations we
require everybody there are homeworks
there are quizzes
will be projects and if the due date is
specified you should submit before the due
date and only in
case that is uncontrollable say if you
have a special case you need to send your
note and say
if you get sick get the get the say
doctors or your your relatives
somebody can can validate your
situation and so that's special case
otherwise you should be on time that is
one thing the other
thing is what of course we are going to
have mostly using programming of
Python and you can use
chat GPT or other language models AI to
assist your learning but you cannot
just copy and paste
submit your homework as whatever
whatever you have see if you have a
problem you really cannot solve
it and you ask the chat GPT to help you
that is fine and after you get the result
after you get
some answer you write down because this
is not originally you make you think
from from your by
you provide the reference say okay if
you go to chat GPT or other other let's
see this any other
any other uh model it allows you to
share so uh tell me
uh uh let's see merge sort this is the
okay let's see this and once you have that
uh result
then there is always a button to
share so go to the share button
okay I will give you the one example of
doing that uh every every model has it
it's at a
different place so once you're shared
it everybody can can see this so the
purpose is to have the
whole dialogue you are not just directly
asking the result uh asking the the
answer so
um you should not copy the problem and
ask chat GPT to do it for you and then
you get answer you
can ask this part please explain and
then you work on from there that is fine
then the whole dialogue
we will show that okay that's the
purpose of doing that I will give you
a concrete example for this
uh they changed the the uh uh cloud change
the uh button for that I will I will
get that later on and
office hour for this course, it will be
Thursday. So we have the Tuesday and
the Thursday. So
Thursday afternoon, right after
the class, it is working hour. You can
go to my office
for questions. If you have a question
during the class, if we can do it in
the class, we
will do it. Normally, if it is very
personal, we want you to go to the office.
If everybody
has a similar question, then we do it in
the class. And before the class,
normally, like
when I do the preparation, you come to
ask me the questions, that is not a
good time
because my mind is not there. I need
to set up everything. So after the
class, right?
So this course will cover three parts.
Assuming everybody already has some
foundational skills
for programming.
And then we will go over the Python
program. However, we will just not
go with the very
basic part. That part is your own job.
You need to make up. If you didn't do
any Python
before, then you need to make it up. I
will give you some resources. And
then after that,
we are going over for the first two
weeks, the object -oriented programming
with Python,
which means we are going to cover with the
Python.
Python class, Python objects, and
user-defined class and objects and
stuff like that because
that is the major application and we are
going to use later on when you do the
machine learning
and other packages. So that is the
big part. And then we will also extend
this for doing
the data structure and the algorithms.
You will see we will use a lot of the
Python class.
And the object and stuff. So for the
algorithms. So we do the two weeks for the
OOP. And then
the remaining part mostly will be like
10 weeks. We will be talking about
theizzegtrichter
and algorithms. This is the key part.And
finally, we will go quickly over
the very basic foundational
skills.
Okay.
database, mostly it will be SQL. Okay,
that's the outline of this course.
So today, I want
everybody just go to your Canvas. So I
have an announcement here. Go to the
announcement
and see the class materials. We have the
strict rule for the class. During the
class, when
I say everybody, you can use
laptop, that's okay, you use laptop. If I
say close laptop
and we want to do something that you
should do on the paper, then you
should not use laptop.
And throughout the class, you
should not use phone. You can
use tablet to take notes, but
do not use phone. Okay?
Okay, I think that's it.
I think we should spend a few minutes
first because this is the first class.
Everybody
wants to introduce yourself a
little bit so everybody knows each other.
Starting from
Wang Huan. Yeah. Introduce yourselves.
Yeah, yeah, turn around. Turn around to
the classmates.
So your name, where you're from, and your
background. Anything that you want to say.
Anything that is, get your classmates to
know about you.
And her name, do she have a number?
And your students?
Yeah do they know all the questions?
No.
No, got them already.
Okay.
okay thank you and my
okay thank you long way
okay thank you
thank you
um
Okay, thank you.
Have you have any other programming
language skills, any experience before?
Okay.
Can you spell your name?
How do you spell your name?
Your name is not here.
Your name is not on Canvas yet.
So make sure you go.
No, no, no, no, that's, that's Wayne.
Oh, me, okay, yeah.
Oh, I'm confused because I always thought
me is a boy.
It can be.
Yeah, all right.
And, hi.
.
. .
All right, thank you about a little
bit of myself, my name is Jen Chi and I
graduated from University of
Chicago with a PhD in atmospheric
science, so I have a science background,
then after graduation my most of my job
is in the research.
I work at NASA jet propulsion
laboratory in California and then.
And late in later I've been there for
15 years I work at also in another
company called the region, which is the
company making missiles for the Defense
contract.
They also work with NASA so my my most
research work is in the earth sciences
atmospheric science and research topics,
including Mars oceans.
And earth atmosphere, then the the
in later years, so the shifting of
the research, this is physical
shifting has there's a trend before
you have the physical models, so you have.
You have the newton's function equations
define your models, how the particles
moves hard atmosphere move the oceans, how
the current moves and then.
Later on, this is not enough, then that's
about 10 years ago.
You want to find out the principles or
patterns from your data, so that is how
emerge how the data science emerged in
every scientific area, and this is.
In what I have worked at there, and so
that is the model you use the statistical
method to model.
Your data and try to find out a
patterns, and so that is the the the way I
got into the data science and the at the
very beginning, there's no term called
the data science and.
In 2018 one one fit in college establish I
came here, I joined a fit in and I also
worked at another pharmaceutical
company called the Merck, which is the
number four pharmaceutical company United
States.
And so I'm doing I did some.
Statistical work for consulting at
that company.
So for this course.
We are going to emphasize on the
foundational skills and knowledge and
we are going to use a lot of projects,
so you, you are going to have a hands
on experience so mostly programming but.
The first thing is for.
For those of you who did not program in
Python very much some of you have some
experience before, but some of you
complete do not have any background,
the first thing is this open this
announcement go to this Kaggle there
is a short tutorial for Python.
And so now everybody follow me.
Kaggle is a platform for data science.
They provide a free running environment so
everybody can run a code in there and they
also offer competitions in data
science, so it is prized competition and.
There are some other competition
that is no price, but the most of the
students many students worldwide join the
competition to form the skills from
the skills for for the data science.
And we are going to.
Also encourage everybody to attend this
and we will pick some of the project
ask you to do it right and then so let's
let's try this.
Once you go there once you once you open
this make sure you're logging Okay, I
already logged in so once you log in you
will you will be you just use your Google
account, you can use your school account
use your school account as your Google
account login.
Once you login you can run it
otherwise you can only do it it is very
important in data science do not Read and
Watch that is not enough that's only
half of the learning you have to do it
hands on you have to do it okay once you
see this, this is this is interactive So
this is notebook you can run and
notebook has the advantage you can.
Not only have the text, you can have
images, you can.
have the code embedded over there. So in
this case, let's see, I will just
quickly go over
this and the remaining part is your own
homework. You need to do this. Within
the first two
weeks, you should finish this, seven
lessons. So with this, not very long,
seven notebooks.
Complete this. And then there
are exercises. There are exercises you
can practice.
So let me show you the exercise.
At the end of the notebook, actually,
there are exercises at the end.
See, your turn. Once you finish
practice with this,
go to your turn.
you can do the exercise over there and
there if you haven't done this so there
are some there are some trick
here you need to go to the you you need
to make
your own copy of the notebook so
say here this way you can edit it so
make a
copy in your own account let me do this
so click click this three dot make a
copy okay now it is in your own account
now you can add it this you can run it
and
this only happens once you log in
okay I'll wait everybody to log in and
make a
copy and then we could go
this one what happens you click on
okay everybody first go over there log in
no once you're logging in the
pop-up Google account that you you choose
logging as Google
okay give me your notebook anybody else
has a problem sorry oh you mean campus
now you use then you use other oh yeah
then you use the person or email okay we
need to open this we need open this
So, use your personal Gmail.
Everybody get in here?
Where's your notebook?
Where's your laptop?
Okay, so next time.
Anybody else has trouble?
Ming?
You don't have a laptop?
Do you have it?
In Duong?
Okay.
So once you get in there, raise your
hand if you are here, you are in this
stage.
Make a copy, no?
What happens?
What's the problem?
What happens if you click on the three
dots?
Yeah, login.
And then once you login, say this, this,
this, click here.
So first, once you click, that's three,
seven lessons, right?
Click on this.
And then click on this.
And then make a copy and edit.
Yeah.
Click on this.
All right.
So once you are in there, once you are
in this, you can, you can see your past
notebook
by clicking.
You can click on your own icon and then
there is, there is your work.
That's list of the notebook you have in
here.
So, but for now you have only one if
you didn't do this before.
So now once you open this, oh, by the way,
everybody, you should audit the
introduction
to computing.
Anybody who did not go in the morning.
That's 830 today.
If you didn't go, raise your hand, let me
know.
Who didn't go?
Okay.
You should go over there.
So, okay.
You, you are fine.
You should go over there.
Everything here is taught in that class.
You audit for that.
You don't, you do not, you do
not need, you can either audit, but
it's preferred audit.
Or you can, you can just sit in, but if
you sit in, you do not have access to
Canvas and
all the homework and assignment,
you do not have those.
So you want to, you want to at least
sit in, but it is preferred everybody go
and audit
this.
Unless you have been doing Python a
lot, a lot in the past, but here,
everybody, no,
I think everybody should go.
All right.
So now I'm quickly going to go over,
over here.
See here.
Now you have a, you have the code.
This is called a code cell.
And you have this, this part, this is
called a text cell.
Double click on this, double click
on this, and you can edit this.
So both cells can be edited.
And once you are done with, with the
editing, click on this running button
and it becomes
this.
It's fixed.
Yeah.
Run over this text cell, then it will
be fixed.
And then for this part, see, this is
assigned zero to this variable and
then make some simple
calculation then with some condition and
the print.
So if you want to run this code, just
click on this, it will run.
See here, that's the output.
And you can also.
You can also modify this.
So you can say, you can add something
to the print.
So let's, let me run this again.
See here.
All right.
That's the, so you, what do you want to do
to learn programming?
The best way to learn programming is
having the code.
That is by somebody else.
Try to understand this.
But how do you understand this?
Just play around with it.
Try to modify and see what happens.
See if your understanding is what you
expected and what you see.
Okay.
That's the best way to learn.
By, by doing it.
And so that is the, the, the,
the, the, the, the, the, the,
the, the, the, the, the, the, the,
the, that is the no book for this.
And let me quickly go over this because we
will go some other notebook later on.
But for this notebook, if you want to
add a new cell.
So let's see.
Here.
I don't want to modify this code.
Because, once I modify, I forget what is
the original code if I mess up.
I'm not able to.
restore so what you can do is you just
copy the code so command a or control a
command a
and to copy the code and then you add a
new cell so you add a new cell so here
you add
see this plus code add a new cell now you
can you can paste here
copy and paste you can move it up upward
so let me move that upward all right so
now once you
do that and then you can modify here so
let's see I I'm not sure whether or not
this would
this work let's see greater equal right so
whether or not this will work
okay this will also work
right so that's the way you do it just
modify it and then so you you can see
result right away the nice thing about
the notebook
for this is it is very interactive
you you'll see the result immediately
okay that is one place to
learn which is Kaggle another place is
Google collab I'm going to give you a
notebook so
I'm going to give you a notebook and
you need to open this
and this notebook is what we are
going to do today and you should finish
the part I which I I deleted
some code I want you to fill it up so
let me share this overview
I'm going to put it on canvas now
so this will be class notebook
this is
the first one all right you should see
this what do you do with this is a
little bit different but very similar
so click on this make sure you log in with
Google account click this and
you are going to see this you're going
to see
this and once you have this you also make
a copy so what do you do so I'll
wait everybody open this open
all right once you open go to file go here
go here
and save a copy in Drive
it will take a few second and open a new
copy and once you open that this
notebook sit in your Google Drive where is
this this thing will be in your go to
your my drive and you are going to see
this yellow folder this yellow photo
called colab notebook it is inside there
you can move you should okay you
should
organize all your class notebook into
some specific folder so for this class
make a folder put everything
in there so it will be easy for you okay
everybody
made a copy all right so let's go over
this by object oriented programming it
means we are not doing the code line by
lines we are doing the code that
we created by writing words so we are not
doing the code diye so all these
calculations that you did are the code
that we figured out with Webplugs it's
going to help you on how to we should
refresh the browser when we have our
browser so I finished up the instruction
and let's go to so Goku's が
we should be able now to solve x 0.16
to solve x 0 .17 and obviously the
little round boast vídeo계
roof and then the doors and then you are
done.
The purpose for this is in when you do
the module,
it will be easy because say you are a
manager for the software development.
Now, if you have the break, break, break,
it will be hard to coordinate.
Now you have the modules.
So this group one, you do this module.
Group two, you do this module.
And after that, you assemble this.
Then for the manager,
what you want to pay attention to
is, let's say I have this wall and the
other wall over there,
but you need to have some kind of a
connection, right?
So you need to define what is
the connection between this module and
this module,
so they can perfectly align together.
So they need to talk to each other.
And what is it you need to do?
You have a similar idea for the
programming.
And in the old days, it is called
procedure programming.
So you just do it line by line or by some
functions.
And then this becomes when the software
becomes more complicated.
And the idea of the modularized
programming language came out.
So that is the object oriented one.
And in the,
in the case of the Python,
we call this thing as class.
Okay, what is class? Class is the module
itself.
Class is design of the module.
You want to design the wall.
So what is your blueprint for the wall?
I want to have three windows.
So you need to specify on your blueprint
three windows.
You also need to say,
what is the other side of the wall?
That is your design.
Once you have the design,
you can produce many,
many different walls.
That many different walls is a concrete.
It is a real wall.
Your definition,
which is the blueprint,
is not a real wall.
It is something,
it's your design.
So the idea for the class,
class is a design.
It's a blueprint.
It's not real.
From the class,
you can create the real stuff.
That is called object.
So that's the two key important concept.
Number one, class.
Class is the blueprint.
It's on the paper.
Okay, it is not a real thing.
On the paper.
And once you have the design,
you can create,
following the design,
create the real stuff.
That is called object.
Okay?
So in Python,
everything is object.
We will see that later on.
Everything is object.
If it is object,
in the object -oriented programming,
it means it has a class.
It is produced from some blueprint.
That blueprint is class.
So let's see this.
In Python,
you can have list.
You can have a string.
You can have a dictionary.
All this is,
should,
you should learn this from the
seven notebooks I just gave you.
So you have the list.
You have a string.
These are the different type of data.
And if you do have this,
let me,
instead of using this,
let me use
even more concrete.
So,
now,
that's your,
I want you to do.
Okay, now,
copy this.
Create a new cell.
Now,
you want to do something that is called a
list.
Now,
in Python,
list is this.
It's square bracket,
now followed by comma.
You can put things inside here.
It does not have to be numbers.
It can,
you can have some string.
String has to be quoted.
Okay, you can mix them together.
But it's a list.
It's just like a shopping list.
So list means object,
object,
object in ordered sequence.
It's a sequence,
right?
So that is this.
Once I have the list,
list has a property called class.
Okay,
that class has a name.
What I'm going to,
what I'm doing here is create a list.
Okay,
that's the first part.
Create a list.
And then,
from that list,
call its property.
Property is like your age,
your name,
your hair color,
your weight,
your height.
That's your attributes.
Now,
the class,
the object also has these attributes.
So one of the attributes is called
underscore,
underscore class.
One,
every time you see this underscore,
underscore,
it means it's built in stuff for Python.
Normally,
you do not need to worry about this
unless you have a special purpose.
It is something hiding from the user.
We are doing this to showcase
so you have a good understanding.
What is a class?
Why do I see everything is object?
So this is object.
And what is the blueprint for this?
That's class.
And this class has a name.
Dot name will show.
So if you run this,
the first line print out.
Okay,
the first time you start this,
see here,
connecting,
it will take some time.
It will allocate a computer for you
from Google.
So you have a unit of computing devices.
You treat this like a real computer.
And then,
one thing you can do is click here.
See,
it tells you,
click here.
It tells you what is the memory
and what is the disk you have.
So see,
I have a 12 gig memory.
I only use the one gig.
And my disk size is 10,
100.
I have used 32.
I didn't use that much
because the 32 is,
you need to have the system,
you have Python,
everything installed there.
So that's the pre-installed.
So here,
this is the class.
The class name is list.
Okay.
Now,
if you do this,
delete this name.
Let's do this.
Without this,
without this,
it will also print.
Now it print,
say,
like this.
What does that mean?
It means I'm printing an object.
This object is belong to a class of list.
All right.
So that means this thing,
it is object.
It is the blueprint for it.
It is class.
That class is this.
And similar for this,
string,
and similar for the dictionary.
So let me change this to the concrete
string.
So string is just,
just this.
Okay.
Quote,
single quote,
double quote,
doesn't matter.
Quote,
and then,
put in some string.
You can have anything.
You can have space.
You can have a single quote inside,
double quote.
And then,
that gave you this.
That gave you the string.
All right.
One nice feature for Python is
it allows you have the string
running multiple lines.
So what you do is
you have a triple quote
starting and ending with triple quote.
So everybody do this.
Now,
triple quote,
you can use single triple quote
or your double triple quote.
And once you do this,
you can have
all,
you can have multiple lines.
All right.
And then,
that will be the same.
That still give you the same.
So that is the string.
And for the dictionary,
let's also do something
for the dictionary.
Dictionary use the curly bracket.
Dictionary is like,
you look up at the dictionary,
right?
You have the,
let's say,
Vietnamese,
Chinese.
All right.
So you have the,
in Vietnamese,
you have the Vietnamese characters.
And for that character,
there's the entry.
Entry is Chinese.
All right.
So now,
you are going to have some,
let's see,
let's,
I'm not able to type Vietnamese,
let me type Chinese.
So,
I type Vietnam in Chinese.
And then,
I will say,
translate of this is,
let's use English.
Okay.
Then,
you are going to have
so that is the way you do for,
you have many,
many entries like this.
Each entry is separated by comma.
Okay.
Now,
not,
not the inside here.
Each entry is separated by,
by comma.
And now,
you can have,
say,
let's use Uno,
which is the Spanish.
And I'm going to use one
for English.
So that's my dictionary.
And that is also,
So when I do the class with the name, and
that's it, this.
One case thing for learning,
whether or not you have been doing well in
college or not,
it is very important to take notes.
Why it is important?
Taking notes as versus just the listening,
the difference is when you actively take
the
notes, instead of just taking the picture,
okay, that's different.
Instead of just taking the picture,
you not only record what has been
taught in the class,
you also process all the information in
your mind, and you make summarize.
Because you cannot write every word.
You have to get the key information
processed through your mind actively.
I'm not talking just in words.
I'm talking based on the data science
studies.
There are many research on this.
Students who actively taking notes
and students who do not, their outcome
is very different.
Also taking notes by typing on the
keyboard and taking notes by handwriting,
it is also
different.
Handwriting is more efficient in learning.
It activates your brain.
It activates your neurons in your mind.
So that is different.
Because when you write this, when you
write down a character, it doesn't matter
if it
is English or Chinese or Vietnamese.
You need to get a picture.
Your mind is, different part in your mind
has been activated, okay?
It is not just when you're typing, only
positional related neurons has
been activated because
there are only 26 keys I typed.
But when you write, it is the whole
picture.
That is different.
But for the code, you do not, you don't
have to use the pencil to write.
Typing the code is fine because here
we want to, we want everybody to run the
code.
You run, you put on the paper, it
doesn't run.
Okay.
So that is different.
However, for the key part, as I said,
when I say, what is class?
What is the object?
What is the relation between class
and object?
What is this?
Okay.
Let me do a quick check.
When you have the dot name and when you
do not have the dot name, what is the
difference?
See here.
When I have the, without the dot name,
and here I do have a dot name, what is the
difference?
Okay.
Let me see this again.
This is what I just said because if you
do not take the notes, you just forget it
right
away.
Remember, before I have this.
I have this.
I have a dot name.
So the printout, the printout is, is list.
Okay.
That's the list.
So what I have here is, first this thing,
this is class object.
Which one?
It is object.
Okay.
This is real stuff.
It is object.
But as I said, in Python, everything is
object.
If it is an object, it will have a
blueprint.
What is the blueprint called?
It's a class.
So what is the class for this?
So I have dot, underscore, underscore,
plus, no, this is the class of this.
However, this thing is another object.
It is not a string of a, called a class.
So now, this is another object.
Is this confusing?
This is object.
And the object has a attribute.
When we have a dot, something, it is an
attribute.
So your name is your attribute.
Your hair color, your height, that's your
attribute.
And this, this is attribute of this
object.
Okay.
And this attribute reference to something
else.
If this is something else, then it
is object.
Remember in Python, everything is
object, right?
So this is object.
We use another object to represent this
class.
Okay.
Everybody get the idea?
This is object.
Object has a class.
That class, how do you, how do you see
that class?
That class is also defined as a class.
Object.
All right.
So, if it is object, then it has
attribute.
One attribute is called an underscore,
underscore, name.
That is what you print out here.
If you do not have this, by default, if
you do not have this, by default,
Python will
try to find out what is the best way
to describe this object.
It has a built -in way to get the string
because once you print, everything has
to be converted
into string.
String is object, right?
So convert everything into string.
So now this class is object.
I need to convert this into some
string and then print out.
That is, that is what you have.
So this is a string.
However, once you have that, that means.
That special representation for that
class, okay?
And that is the, that is the dot and
the internal stuff.
This is internal, built-in stuff.
Another important stuff, another important
part, part is this.
So I have this list.
I did the same.
I add another class.
Remember, I, when I have this.
This is the attribute of the list, right?
Attribute of the list is another object.
So if it is object, it has a class.
Now, what is the class of this thing?
It also has a class.
And what is the class?
What is the name for this?
It is the type.
Okay.
When you have class as a list, class as
a string.
Class as a dictionary.
All these become one, there's a,
when you see the class, it is like a
parent.
Parent can have sons and daughters.
Because this is produced from the same
blueprint, right?
So now the parent is the class.
That parent is called a type.
That is data type.
In Python, there are many different data
types.
Each data type is a class.
But if you, if you call everything as
general, it is type.
It is data type.
So that's why you have this.
This is type.
Okay.
The key thing for this part is everything
is object.
Every object has attribute.
If you do dot something, that's access
to that object.
The attribute.
That attribute can be an object of
another class.
Okay?
So it is object of object.
All right?
And then, now let's see one example of the
class now.
Okay.
Let me pause a little bit here.
Make sure everybody okay with the idea
of object class attribute.
Three key things.
Okay.
One is object class attribute.
Make sure you do not mix, do not confuse.
Everybody okay?
Questions?
Yes?
Yeah.
That's, when I say parent, it
means, here it means class.
So when you have this, what is the
class of this?
This is the class of type.
Okay.
You can all, if you go everything for
the class and class on the very, very
top, there
is one single class that is called object.
It's just object.
In Python, this object means the parent, a
grandparent of everything, because
everything
is object.
Okay.
So you have the thing like, so now I
have this, this, and this, and this.
So the object for me is, is I object.
Right.
Yes.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's nested.
Every class can have object.
Every object must have a class.
Yes.
If you go for the class of class of class
of class, go to the top, it is one single
object.
That object is called, just called object.
That's it.
So it doesn't go any further.
That's built in.
That is built in for Python.
Okay.
In this case, we want to do a quick
demonstration for the object
and the class.
So what we want to do is if you open
the notebook, I think some of the, some
of the function
I have deleted the code.
So your notebook will be different
from mine.
Your job is after the class, you
fill up what has been missing.
It's your job.
So let's go over this.
When you define a class, you just use the
class.
See the blue one?
That means, this is called a keyword.
Keyword is reserved.
That means when you define some
function, you define your own variables,
do not use
the same, exactly the same thing.
Because you are messing up with, otherwise
you're messing up the built in stuff.
This is reserved for Python.
Okay.
Do not use exactly class as your
function name or your, your variable name.
Okay.
So now I have a definition for the class
and the name for that is called a
credit card.
Now I have a blueprint.
Let's say it's, this is the Bank of
America.
Okay.
I'm going to produce the credit card
from Bank of America.
And then this thing.
It always has a function.
This one, this is the definition of
function, DEF is definition of function.
And this is the function, function name.
Why do I have underscore, underscore in
it?
Every time when you have underscore,
underscore, it means you want to hide this
thing from
users.
Okay.
You want to hide this.
The advantage for hiding this is only,
let's say.
Only advanced users can mess up with this.
Do not do it if you do not understand it.
So that is the purpose.
So regular users do not see it.
They will not be able to mess up with
this.
And then why this, this is important for
this specific function.
This will be called, this function will
be called every time you create a new
object.
So we will see this later on.
And then it has a first parameter.
In function call, you always have
many different parameters.
But it is okay if you do not have any
parameter.
So you can have a function that
is empty like this.
That is fine.
In Python.
In Python syntax, it is okay.
It doesn't give you error.
However, for this specific function,
init, inside the class, it is required
you have
a first parameter reserved as a
reference to the object itself.
So you need to have, normally you call it,
call it itself.
Okay.
That means, because this is Blueprint.
This is Blueprint.
Once you print, create a new credit
card, self means that concrete real
stuff is self.
Okay.
And because this Blueprint is not the
real stuff.
And then you can have some other stuff to
plug in your functions.
All right.
So for functions, anybody okay
with the idea of function?
The function is the same.
The function is the same as you have
learned in algebra.
Okay.
So you have a function.
You have some input.
Then you do some calculation.
You output something, right?
In the case of init, this is something
reserved.
You always have the first parameter as
self.
And then you have other stuff.
Here, I would say this will be the name,
which will be a string, name of the
customer.
And then I will say the bank.
Okay.
In the case of Bank of America, it is
just the name Bank of America.
Remember what is printed on your credit
card, your name, your bank, right?
And then the account number, 16
digit account number.
Okay.
And there is other thing, that is the
every credit card has a limit, has a
credit limit.
You cannot charge over the limit.
Let's say $2 ,000, okay?
So that's the thing why you create the
credit card in the very beginning.
You want to have.
So that's the information here.
And then let's forget about the expiration
and the pin number.
Let's simplify this now.
Questions?
Yes.
To identify the function, this is the
name of the function.
Yeah.
But when you call this function, you
do not call underscore, underscore, init.
We will see how you call this function
later on.
Okay.
This is because this is a special
function.
It is called automatically.
You do not call it.
Python will call it for you.
Right.
Automatically.
Yeah.
So, now, once you have this, what you do
is, because you are creating a new
credit card,
that credit card is the real thing.
This is blueprint.
That real thing is, has a reference
called self.
Now, in this case, the name is the
attribute of the credit card.
The.
The bank is attribute of the credit card.
The account number is attribute.
So what you do is you define the customer
name, the bank, account, limit, and the
balance,
everything as attributes.
Attached to self.
Remember, self is the real credit card.
Once you create the real credit card, it's
referenced as self.
So, this is the real credit card.
Again, when I use underscore, it
means this is internal thing.
I do not want my customer to modify by
himself.
See, if you really have a credit card,
you bank does not allow user to modify the
name
or the account number.
You cannot do it.
All right.
So, we use underscore as a way to
represent this action.
Okay.
Yeah.
You hide this.
And then.
But in the beginning, you have zero
balance.
So that is this.
And then, what you do is let
me let's first ignore the remaining part.
Run this.
Now, everybody, if you have the
notebook open, run this cell.
Run this cell.
And then, once you have this, and what you
do is you can do this.
You create a new object.
This new object is.
Okay.
This is the name.
Class name is credit card.
Right?
Put the name of the class and like
calling a function for this.
Put this as the parameter, which is the
name bank.
Let's see.
Bank of America.
And then, let's see.
You should have 16 numbers.
And then, you put the limit.
So.
Once you do that, and you can print out
what is CC.
So, this is called assign.
We do not say equal.
If you say equal, it is prone to get
errors for your understanding.
Some students are confused by assigning
to the right -hand side.
When you say assign, it means I have
something on the left-hand side.
I want to put what I have on
the right-hand side to my left-hand side.
Okay.
Always read this from right to left.
So, it means call this function.
In this case, it is class.
It is not a function.
Call this class create object.
Now you have object.
This is real.
It is a real credit card.
It has name.
It has limit.
It has account number.
And then, assign it to CC.
So, this CC, when you print out, it is
this.
It is in the main, which is your program.
The object of the whole program called
main.
And inside main, there is a credit card
at this memory position.
In some memory position.
Python knows how to get there.
You don't need to know that.
Okay.
It is just something set in your memory.
So, when I shut down my computer,
let's see this.
If you go over here, close this, then
it's gone.
Everything is gone.
And because this is in the memory, and
it's gone.
You do not have access to it.
Unless you save this in disk.
And by the way, one thing.
So, go here.
Runtime.
Runtime allows you to interrupt.
And allows you to disconnect.
So, why do you do the disconnect?
When you finish using this notebook, just
disconnect this.
The reason is everybody has limited hours
to use the free notebook from Google.
If you use up for today, then you
cannot use anymore.
Tomorrow, you will have another.
Let's see.
Three hours.
Everybody has three hours every day.
So, if you finish, just close it.
Do not use.
Let it running.
Use up your quota.
Do not let it running.
And if you close this tab, it also closes.
Okay.
But that will take some time.
Not immediately.
And that is the way you create object.
And as I said.
Everything is object.
If you type object, that's the top object
for everything.
It is internal object.
Okay.
And then we define something as a
function.
Now, I define a function.
This function in the class is called
method.
Because why it is called method?
It is like this.
You have object.
Now, these are the method.
Because once you push.
Some action happens.
All right.
So, that's the same.
When I push this button.
It is going to have something is going to
happen.
So, in this case, what I want to do is
when I push this button.
What I want is give me the name of the
customer.
So, dot underscore customer gave
me the name of the customer.
So, that what you return.
That is why you call the function.
It will return.
One thing I didn't mention before.
In the example is this.
This is internally called as I said.
When does this call?
See, if you have this line.
Class name followed by the parentheses.
It will call the underscore, underscore
init function.
It will call this function.
When this function has been called.
First thing is create.
It an object.
And assign it as self.
And then.
This is the first parameter when
you create this.
See, the first parameter.
John Doe.
It's not self.
This thing is defined as the second.
Okay.
Let me stress this again.
When you call a function.
What happens?
So, when you call a function.
You have a class.
Okay.
Which is Blueprint.
Inside the class.
You have this function.
That's a special function.
And now.
This is a credit card.
Credit card.
Plus.
Now I call this.
Credit card.
I call this function.
By.
Let's see the customer name.
And the bank account limit.
Okay.
When I call this.
When I create new credit card.
From this.
Okay.
What happens is.
After Python see this.
See this line.
It will first go over the reference of
this.
Class.
And find out what is this.
And then.
Create a real object.
Let's see the real object.
Is this.
Credit card.
Okay.
Create a credit card.
That's a real credit card.
But for now.
It doesn't have a name.
Doesn't have an account number yet.
It's the plastic.
Now.
Go over here.
Put this thing.
As self.
That's the first step.
Create it.
And.
Reference this as self.
And then.
Now you call this function.
Next step is call this function.
Because this function says.
First parameter is self.
So you have to have.
Something called self.
First.
Then you call this function.
So.
That self for now is the blank plastic
stuff.
And you put this.
Put it here as self.
And then you put other things.
Other than name.
Account number.
Bank.
Limit.
And once you have that.
It will use the dot.
Something dot.
Something.
To attach to that.
That.
That means this.
Create.
Something.
On your credit card.
So that's the whole idea of the.
Class and object.
Just remember now.
Okay.
This thing.
That's the blueprint.
After you call the init function.
It gave you a real credit card.
It is real stuff.
It has the name and everything else.
Okay.
So that is the way.
This.
Work.
And then.
We are going to have some other things.
We have.
Function called.
Get.
Customer.
And this function.
See here.
Now.
It has only self.
It doesn't have anything else.
So how do you call this function.
When you call this function now.
Everybody follow me.
CC dot.
Then you get.
Customer.
All right.
That's the way you call it.
You do not need to put self.
Where is self now.
Self is here.
See.
CC is self.
So everybody understand the logic.
When you call this function.
Get.
Customer.
It is actually calling this function.
However.
The self is now attached to CC.
You do not need to put anything here.
Just put empty.
And then.
It will give you.
John Doe.
Okay.
That is what we have here.
See here.
Everybody.
Get this.
Okay.
That's the way.
It works.
And.
Now.
This.
This is.
This is a.
Object.
CC is object.
Yes.
Right.
Okay.
Let me repeat this again.
This is Blueprint.
From the Blueprint.
You want to create a real credit card.
How do you do it?
Just write down the same class name.
Followed by the parentheses.
Then.
You put in all the required parameters for
this class.
In this case.
Is everything except of self.
So.
Now.
First thing is.
Custom name.
That's John Doe.
Bank of America.
And account number.
And 1000 limit.
And then.
After that.
A new credit card has been produced.
So.
Let's call it CC.
Once you have that.
CC.
Then.
Now.
Everything defined as the.
See.
I have indentation here.
Class indent.
Everything defined inside the class.
Now is attribute.
It's like attribute.
But.
Actually this attribute is a function.
We call this method.
And the way to call that is.
Use.
CC.
And once you call this.
This CC will plug into self.
So.
When you call this.
Get customer.
This CC.
Will jump.
Here.
Once you have CC jumped here.
Then.
Because.
Previously.
You attached John Doe to CC.
Now.
You can get it.
John Doe out.
Everybody.
Get the idea.
So.
That's the way it works.
Now.
And then.
You can get the other thing.
Get bank.
Get account.
And.
Now.
A little bit more.
Complicated is charge.
So.
Now.
You have a credit card.
You swipe.
Now.
You charge this.
But.
You do not want to just charge.
Arbitrarily.
First.
You want to make sure.
You do not over.
Your limit.
So.
If you want to.
If you want to buy a laptop.
With 1000 limit.
Probably.
You will not be able to do it.
And then.
So.
The first.
Thing.
The first thing.
You want to do is.
You want to compare.
That.
When you charge.
With the price.
You already have.
Some balance.
In the very beginning.
It is zero.
And then.
After you.
You.
Charge.
Many times.
It.
Accrued.
The balance.
And then.
The total.
Total.
New balance.
Will be.
The price.
Plus.
The existing balance.
You make sure.
If.
This is.
Over the limit.
You.
Are not going to.
Succeed.
In charging.
This.
Otherwise.
It is.
Succeed.
You are going to.
Add the price.
To your balance.
And.
You return.
The Boolean.
In this case.
Is true.
Okay.
Success.
And.
Then.
See.
If you want to make.
A payment.
This.
You use.
The plus.
Because.
Every time.
You add.
The balance.
You charge.
It.
But.
If you want.
To pay out.
Your.
Credit card.
You subtract.
The balance.
Right.
So.
If you pay.
Some amount.
You subtract.
The amount.
So.
When you.
Have this.
That means.
You have.
This thing.
Let me.
Write down.
Something.
It will be.
This.
Amount.
Okay.
That's.
Exactly.
The same.
As this.
You have.
Minus.
Equal.
That is.
This.
It is doing.
Subtracting.
On itself.
Okay.
That is.
The.
The first.
Thing.
We are.
Doing.
For.
The.
Class.
And.
Object.
Make.
Sure.
You.
Want.
To.
After.
The.
Skills.
And.
The.
Concept.
Okay.
We will stop.
Here.
Today.
Thank.
You.